没人相信爱丽丝
No one believed Alice
所说的仙境冒险
when she spoke of her adventures in wonderland
她是如何爱上精灵塞勒斯
Of how she fell in love with a Genie named Cyrus
红心王后又是如何拆散他们的
And how the Red Queen tore them apart.
不
No!
她被关进一家精神病院
She was locked away in an asylum.
爱丽丝  她需要帮助
Alice. She needs help.
所以红桃杰克和我带她回了仙境
So the Knave of Hearts and I brought her back to Wonderland
寻找她的真爱
to search for her true love.
他在这里  我能感觉到
He's here. I can feel it.
有人想阻止她
There are those who will try to stop her.
让那个女孩许下三个愿
What we want can't be accomplished
我们的目的才能达成
until the girl's made all her wishes.
但是爱丽丝的伟大冒险
But alice's greatest adventure
刚刚开始
has just begun.
《仙境奇缘》前情提要
Previously in Wonderland...
父亲  是我
Father, it's me!
你绝对不会相信我去了哪里
You're never going to believe where I've been!
爱丽丝
Alice.
你把魔尘给我弄来
You get me the dust,
我就帮你找你的精灵
and I'll help you find your Genie.
因为今天我们就将逃离此地
Today's the day we get out of here.
现在我想出去走走
I'd like to take a trip now.
-去哪  -你知道去哪
- Where to? - You know where.
我想去贝特莱姆皇家医院
I'm looking for Bethlem Royal Hospital.
离这里远吗
Is it near?
这是...
What is...
你是...
Who are...
贝特莱姆  精神病院
Bethlem. The asylum.
在哪里
Where is it?
往东走
East of here,
过了威斯敏斯特大桥就是
Just past Westminster Bridge.
看吧
See?
这不是很容易嘛
That wasn't so difficult, was it?
不得不夸您一句
And I must compliment you.
这套西装真不错
That is a very nice suit.
贝特莱姆精神病院
鸦片酊
你好
Hello?
请问有什么事吗
Can I help you?
但愿如此
I certainly hope so.
我是谢菲尔德医生
My name is Dr. Sheffield.
我刚刚来到伦敦
I've just arrived in London
想向您请教一下
and I was hoping to pick your brain
之前一个病人的问题
about a former patient?
没问题  我一向乐于为同行帮忙
Yes, of course. Always happy to help a colleague.
进来吧  请坐
Come in. Have a seat
我这里有点乱请别介意
You'll have to excuse the mess
没想到会有客人来
I wasn't expecting anyone.
没关系
That's quite all right.
我想这里的访客应该不多
I imagine you don't get many visitors here.
大多数人对精神病院都有抵触
Most people tend to avoid asylums.
他们担心会受到这里...
They worry there might be something...
负面情绪的影响
contagious in the air.
请问您要询问哪位病人呢
So, uh, which patient were you after?
金发  蓝眼
Blonde hair, blue eyes.
你一定记得她
I'm sure you remember her.
名字叫爱丽丝
Name of Alice.
我貌似不记得
I don't recall
哪个病人叫爱丽丝
any Alice, I'm afraid.
我们这里病人太多了
We have so many patients.
你一定记得
Well, of course you do.
能有几个病人会跟
But how many of them escape
一只会说话的兔子结伴逃跑呢
in the company of a talking rabbit?
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you mean.
真的吗  就算是亲眼看到也不相信吗
Really? Even after you saw it with your own two eyes?
会说话的兔子
A talking rabbit?
太离谱了
That's madness.
有时候最离谱的故事
Sometimes the maddest stories...
才是最可信的
are the truest ones.
快拿走
Put it away.
求你了
Please.
我一直在努力忘掉那件事
I've tried so hard to forget.
好吧
Yes, well...
我希望你现在能够回忆起来
What I need you to do now is remember.
你的专长是探知人们的思想
Your speciality is getting inside heads.
现在  我要探知她的一切
Now... I want to get inside hers.
我需要了解爱丽丝的所有事
I need to know everything about Alice.
有人吗
Hello?
贾法尔
Jafar?
我觉得他不在这里  陛下
I don't think he's here, your Majesty.
我觉得这里没人  亲爱的
I don't think anyone's here, darling.
贾法尔  卫兵都不见踪影
Not Jafar, not the guards,
最重要的是精灵也不在了
and more importantly, the Genie.
现在我非常好奇
Now this has got me quite curious.
如果有谁能告诉他们去哪了
If only someone could tell me where they went.
我或许是贾法尔的犯人
I may be Jafar's prisoner,
但不是你的
but I'm not yours.
我不会回答你的任何问题
You will get no answers from me.
没必要这么粗鲁
Oh, now, no need to be rude.
我们彼此还不了解呢
We don't even know one another.
现在了解了
Yes, now we do.
我可以一直这样  直到把你摔死
I can continue doing that until you're dead...
或者你可以张嘴说话
or you can talk.
贾法尔走了
Jafar is gone.
我不知道他去哪了
I don't know where he went.
但他把塞勒斯也带走了
But he brought Cyrus with him.
亲爱的  这笼子已经破了
Darling, the cage has been cut open.
贾法尔想带他走  用钥匙就可以了
If Jafar wanted to take him, he'd have used the key!
无所谓  你永远抓不到他
It doesn't matter. You will never catch him.
为什么
Why is that?
因为他身上蕴藏着世间最强大的力量
Because he carries with him the greatest power of all.
真爱
True love.
他在哪
where is he?!
爱丽丝  你在哪
Alice, where are you?
我只要跟随下山的太阳
All I have to do is follow the sun west
就能找到你
and I'll find you.
坚持住  爱丽丝
Stay strong, Alice.
我来找你了
I'm coming for you.
不许动  你这是要去哪啊
Hold on there. Where do you think you're headed?
我往西走
I'm heading west.
去找个人  你挡路了
I need to find someone, and you're blocking my way.
如果你一直往西走
If you keep heading west,
就会走进黑森林  亲爱的
you'll end up in the black forest, love.
在哪里谁到找不到
You won't find anyone there.
据说那里是黑暗之地
They say it's so dark,
连自己的鼻子都看不到
you can't even find your own nose.
我决定碰碰运气  谢了
I'll take my chances. Thank you.
这样做似乎很冒险  对吧
That seems awful dangerous, don't it?
一个女孩独自出行
A little girl traveling alone.
也许她不知道规矩
She might not know the rules.
有很多路是收费的  你得交买路钱
See, this here's a toll road. You needs to pay the toll.
乖乖的吧
Now be a good girl...
把项链给我们
And give us that necklace.
你敢碰这项链  我就把你手砍下来
You even touch this necklace, and you'll lose your hand.
说话注意点  亲爱的
Careful who you threaten, luv.
不要舍命不舍财
No bauble's worth losing your life.
我就是不舍
This one is.
说话注意点  亲爱的
Be carefulwho you threaten... Luv
谢谢你们的火把
Thanks for the light.
我已经失去了你一次
I already lost you once before.
我绝不会重蹈覆辙
I'm not gonna lose you again.
英格兰  维多利亚时代
一年前
不
No.
塞勒斯
Cyrus?
cyrus?
不
No...
No.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我没事
Yes, I'm fine.
我只是
I'm just...
只是迷路了
just a little lost.
我在找回家的路
I'm trying to find my way home.
你住在附近吗
Do you live near here?
以前是
I used to.
很早以前
A long time ago.
-米莉  你在哪  -米莉
- Millie, where are you? - Millie!
我父母  他们一定能帮你
My parents--I'm sure they can help you.
在这里
Over here!
米莉
Oh, Millie.
跟你说过不要到处乱跑的
What have we told you about running off?
我只是想帮忙
But I'm only trying to help.
她找不到家了
She can't find her way home.
父亲
Father.
爱丽丝
Alice?
我的天呐  你还活着
Oh, my god. You're alive.
父亲  他不在了
Oh, father. He's gone.
谁不在了
Who's gone?
塞勒斯  被她杀了
Cyrus. She killed him.
我不明白  爱丽丝
I don't understand. Alice...
你这么多年都去哪了
Where have you been all these years?
塞勒斯是谁
Who's Cyrus?
我要嫁的人
The man I was going to marry.
但是红心王后  把他杀了
But the Red Queen... She killed him.
-把他杀了  -别说了
- She killed him. - Hush.
你回家了
You are home now.
我们回头再说
We can talk about all this later.
父亲  这个姑娘是谁
Father, who is this girl?
这是爱丽丝
This is Alice.
你的姐姐
She's your sister.
同父异母的姐姐
Your half-sister.
你从没说起过我有个姐姐
You never told me I had a sister.
父亲
Father...
爱丽丝  你走了以后发生了很多事
Alice, so much has changed since you left.
我给你介绍一下米莉
I'd like to introduce you to Millie.
还有
And this--
这是你的继母  莎拉
this is your new mother-- Sarah.
我们现在是一家人了
This... this is your family now.
王后大道的尽头
进入者请放弃一切希望
"Abandon all hope ye who enter."
往回走
我什么都不会放弃  尤其是希望
I'm not going to abandon anything, certainly not hope.
请注意
前方是黑森林
这纯粹是浪费木材
Seems like an awful waste of wood,
竖一块牌子还不够吗
when one sign would do.
前方是无尽的黑夜
真有这么可怕吗
I mean, is it really that bad?
好了  爱丽丝
Okay, Alice...
一点点黑暗算不了什么
A little bit of darkness won't hurt anybody.
该死的  我的头
Bloody hell, my head.
拜托  老兄  能让我喝口水吗
Please, mate, can I get a sip of that water?
你没事吧  看起来气色不好
Are you okay? You don't look too good.
你被石化过吗
You ever been stoned?
像死了一样的感觉
Feels like death when you come out of it.
可能你吸的不是真货吧
Maybe you've been messing with the wrong stuff.
不  我是说"石化"  被变成石头
No, I mean "Stoned" As in turned to stone.
好吧  好吧
Sure. Sure.
真的
Yeah.
给你
Here.
全都给你了
Take the whole thing.
红桃杰克
Knave of Hearts.
请给和你一路的女魔头
We've got a message for that she-devil
带个口信
you've been traveling with.
爱丽丝  你们见到她了吗
Alice? You've seen her?
她是个疯子
She's mad, that one.
趁我们睡觉的时候  无缘无故的攻击我们
Attacked us for no reason while we were sleeping.
你告诉她  如果让我们再见到她
You tell her, If we meet again,
我们绝不会手软
we won't go easy.
没问题
Of course.
不过你们两个混蛋得先给我指个路
If you lads could point me in the right direction.
她刚刚救了我的命  我得找到她
Look, she just saved my life. I have to find her.
祝你好运吧
Well, good luck with that.
她往黑森林去了
She's headed to the black forest.
黑森林
The black forest?
该死的
Bloody hell.
对  如我们所说
Yeah. Like we said,
好运吧
good luck.
一直走直线
Keep walking in a straight line.
一直  朝  西走
Keep... walking... west.
不
Oh, no.
不要灭啊  求你了
Please stay alight. Please.
不要  不要  不要
No, no, no. No!
我过来了
I made it through.
我就知道不远了
I knew I was close.
感觉太棒了
That feels so wonderful.
很美吧
Beautiful, isn't it?
让你感觉非常  闲适
Makes you feel quite... mimsy.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是木匠
I'm the carpenter.
你是谁
Who are you?
我不太想让你知道我的名字
I'm not sure I want to give you my name.
你知道这是什么地方吗
Do you know where we are?
我一直试图定位方向
I've been trying to find my bearings.
这里是米堡果林
We are in the Boro Grove,
世上最美的地方
The most beautiful place in the world.
何不放下你的宝剑
Why don't you put down your sword
感觉一下
and stay a while?
我不可能留下来
I couldn't possibly.
我有很重要的事要做
I've got quite important things to do.
有什么事比晒太阳更重要呢
What could be more important than basking in the sun?
救人
S-s... saving... someone's life.
我一直跟着太阳
I-I've been, uh, following the sun,
我是说
and, uh, I mean...
我正在寻找
I'm trying to find, uh...
一个精灵
there's... Uh, there's this genie,
可是他
and he's, uh...
他遇到了麻烦
he's in trouble, and, uh...
至少我觉得他遇到了麻烦
uh, uh... at least I thought he was.
我突然不太记得了
Uh, s-suddenly I can't quite remember.
那你就要留下
Then you must stay.
这里挺漂亮的
It is quite beautiful here.
也许我该在这儿待会儿
Maybe I will stay a while.
她打算在这待多久
How long is she planning to stay?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
你不担心她吗
Aren't you concerned about her--
先让我和她聊聊吧
Let me talk to her. Please.
但愿我们有个像样的卧室
I wish we had a proper bedroom...
或是换洗的衣物
or a change of clothes.
当然我们可以给你买新的
We can get you new things, of course.
我想知道的是
What I would like to know...
你这次打算在这留多久
how long are you planning on staying this time?
再也不走了
Forever.
仙境没有值得我留恋的东西了
There's nothing left for me in Wonderland.
爱丽丝
Alice...
有些事情你必须要明白
there's something you must understand.
我已经有了一个新家
I have a new family now,
他们也会像我一样爱你
and they will love you as I do.
可是米莉
But Millie...
她年纪还很小  而且容易受到影响
is quite young and impressionable.
如果你真的要留下来
If you truly want to stay,
就不能再提仙境
there can be no more mention of Wonderland...
或是那个精灵
or this... genie.
他叫塞勒斯
He had a name. Cyrus.
爱丽丝
Alice...
不管你到底去了哪里
wherever you really were...
不管发生了什么事
whatever really happened,
你最好把这些事都忘了
these things are best forgotten.
难道我要将他遗忘
So I should just sweep him under the rug,
就像你对妈妈
like you did with mother...
和对我那样吗
and with me?
我沉溺于过去痛苦的回忆中
I spent a long time clinging
已经太久了
to painful memories.
直到有一天我才发现  我必须放手
And then one day I realized I had to stop clinging...
才能拥有快乐
to be happy.
但要是没有了他
I don't think I can be happy again...
我再也不会快乐了
and not without him.
你会快乐的
You will be...
只要你愿意住在这个家里
if you want to live in this house.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
你能试着融入我们
Can you try to fit in,
在这个家里重拾欢乐吗
to be happy in our home?
我已经无处可去了
I have nowhere else to go.
我会试试
I'll try.
那么你会忘记仙境
And you will forget about Wonderland?
忘记塞勒斯吗
And this Cyrus?
爱丽丝
Alice.
我回来你高兴吗  父亲
Are you glad... I'm back, father?
你真的想要我留下吗
Do you really want me here?
我当然想  爱丽丝
Of course I do, Alice.
当然了
Of course.
塞勒斯是从这逃走的
Cyrus ran this way.
贾法尔那些卑鄙的守卫都在紧追其后
Jafar's filthy guards-- they all ran after him.
好极了  那他们很快就能抓到他了
Good. Then they'll have him apprehended in no time.
恰恰相反  我的小傻瓜
That, my little dimwit,
我们才不想他被抓到
is precisely what we do not want.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你当然不懂了  你俩双胞胎兄弟啥都不懂
Of course you don't. You tweedles never do--
一个比一个笨
Each one dumber than the next.
可是王后陛下  你不能独自去追捕他
But your majesty can't go after him alone, and...
而且这身打扮也不适合一位王后
that outfit is not befitting a queen.
不要对我
Do not tell me
指手画脚
what I can and can't do!
每个人都在低估我
Everyone keeps underestimating me.
我又不是一开始就是王后
I was not always queen.
我知道怎么做那些肮脏的勾当
I know how to get my hands dirty.
是的
Of course.
如果我独自抓到精灵
If I alone capture the genie,
我就会得到他和他的瓶子
I will have him and his bottle.
我就会得到一切
I will have everything.
贾法尔将会一无所有  而我将会
Jafar will have nothing, and I win...
成为这场游戏的赢家
the game.
爱丽丝
Alice!
爱丽丝  你
Alice, are you--
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
是瓶该死的香水吗
Is this a bloody perfume bottle?
你来了
You're here!
找到你了
Found ya.
你安然无恙
And you're in one piece.
看来我们俩都没事了
I guess we're both okay.
我还担心你来着
You had me worried for a bit.
什么也不要担心
Don't worry about anything.
这里的一切都太美好了
Everything is wonderful here.
你一定要来看看这个
You've got to see this!
慢一点
Slow down.
快来
Come on!
这是什么鬼东西
What the hell is that?
我做的  是不是很漂亮
I made it. Isn't it pretty?
这里到底是怎么回事
What the bloody hell is going on here?
他是谁
Who's that?
只是个木匠  不用担心他
Oh. That's just the carpenter. Don't worry about him.
不要担心一个拿着锯子
Right. Don't worry about the man
笑容诡异的人
with the saw and the scary grin.
说对了
Exactly.
你在这多久了  爱丽丝
How long have you been here, Alice?
不记得了
I don't remember.
有一会了吧
A while.
你把项链摘下来  就这样什么都不干
And you took the necklace off and just stopped everything
只摘花吗
to pick flowers?
可塞勒斯还被关押着对吗
With Cyrus still a prisoner?
是的
Yes?
为什么要这样
Why would you do that?
因为这样我会很开心
Because it makes me happy.
回到家  我真的很高兴
I really am so happy to be back.
谢谢你给我的新裙子
Thank you for my new dress.
我非常喜欢这些雏菊的香味
I really love the smell of those daisies.
那是大丽花  亲爱的
They're dahlias, dear.
大丽花  当然了  我一定会记住的
Dahlias. Of course. I must remember that.
我觉得你穿那条裙子很漂亮  爱丽丝
I think you look beautiful in that dress, Alice.
当然很漂亮
Of course she does,
所以我想我们该谈谈她的社会责任
which is why I think we should talk about her social obligations...
既然她死而复生了
now that she's back from the dead.
-社会责任  -我不是想讨人厌
- Social obligations? - Well, I don't want to put a fine point on it,
但你已经不是个小姑娘了
but you're not a little girl anymore.
是的  当然不是
No, of course not.
一个年轻女性应该考虑一下自己的未来
And a young woman should think about her future.
莎拉  拜托  她才刚刚回来
Sarah... Please. She's only just returned.
所以我们更加应该帮忙
All the more reason we have to help.
帮忙  怎么说
Help? With what, exactly?
当然是把你介绍给合适的年轻人
Meeting a suitable young man, of course.
让你继续生活
Moving on with your life.
我已经跟住在路那头的达西夫人说了
I've been speaking with Mrs. Darcy down the road.
她的儿子还没结婚  有工作
Her son is unmarried, employed,
而且也不太难看
and not awful to look at.
我们已经说好哪天一起喝茶了
We've arranged for a tea.
我只是...我不能这样
I just... I just couldn't.
恐怕你必须如此
I'm afraid you must.
我都已经安排好了
I've already made the arrangements.
只是喝茶罢了 爱丽丝
It's just tea, Alice.
你肯定能做到的
Surely you can manage that much.
达西家的儿子会出来帮着打圆场的
The Darcy boy will carry on both halves of the conversation.
你只需要微笑就可以了
All you have to do is smile.
这对你有好处  爱丽丝
This could be good for you, Alice--
是一种  你知道的
A way to, you know...
让你忘掉烦恼的方法
forget your troubles.
爱丽丝
Alice.
到底怎么回事
What on earth?
天啊  我很抱歉
oh, god. I'm so sorry.
我只是现在还没准备好见任何年轻男士
I'm simply not ready for meeting any young men right now.
我想忘掉某些烦恼需要多花一点时间
I think some troubles take a bit longer to forget.
他往哪边走了
Where did he go?
他往这边跑了
well, he went this way!
这边
This way.
他过河了  你们俩往那边走
He's in the river. You two that way.
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
你们跟着我  找到他的时候
You lot with me. And when you find him,
记住  那个混蛋杀了我们一个兄弟
remember, that bastard killed one of ours.
让他见见血
So make him bleed.
遵命  长官  跟我来
Yes, sir. Come with me.
走吧  爱丽丝  我们得去找塞勒斯
come on, Alice. We've got to find Cyrus.
再过一会儿吧
Maybe in a little while.
你摸过这些树的树皮吗  非常可爱
Have you felt the bark on this tree? It's lovely.
我不想摸这些破树皮
I don't want to feel the bloody bark.
我想让你恢复过来
I want you to snap out of it.
恢复什么啊
Snap out of what?
-爱丽丝  你怎么了  -没什么
- Alice, what's wrong with you? - Nothing.
头一遭啊  我的生活中什么麻烦都没有
For the first time in my life, nothing's wrong.
我很开心  他很开心
I'm happy. He's happy.
为什么你不开心
Why aren't you?
你对爱丽丝做了什么
What have you done to Alice?
我问你  你对她做了什么
I said, what did you do to her?
听着  我一般比较善良
Listen, I'm more of a lover, generally.
但如果你不说的话
but if you don't talk,
我就会把你揍到说出答案为止
I will knock an answer out of you.
伙计  你那里有东西
Mate, you got something.
该死
Bloody hell!
天啊
Oh, god.
这可不妙
This is not good.
它让你想要留下来
It makes you want to stay.
爱丽丝
Alice!
爱丽丝  爱丽丝
Alice! Alice!
爱丽丝  爱丽丝  我们得立刻离开这里
Alice, Alice, we have to get out of here right bloody now.
爱丽丝
Alice.
爱丽丝是谁
Who's Alice?
不  塞勒斯
No. Cyrus.
塞勒斯
Cyrus!
不
No!
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
爱丽丝
Alice?
Alice!
米莉
Millie.
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing in here?
我听到你在尖叫
I heard you screaming.
我做噩梦了  没什么  回去睡觉吧
It's just a bad dream, that's all. Go back to bed.
爸爸说我们不该害怕恶梦
Father says you should never be afraid of your bad dreams,
因为那不是真的
because they're not real.
的确像是父亲的话
That certainly sounds like father.
但是你的恶梦是真的吗
Are your bad dreams real, though?
所以你才在吃饭的时候捏碎了那个杯子
Is that why you broke that glass at dinner?
别说了  去睡吧
That's enough. Off to bed.
至少告诉我  谁是塞勒斯
At least tell me who Cyrus is.
你说什么
What did you say?
塞勒斯  你一直在叫他的名字
Cyrus. You kept yelling his name.
他是谁
Who is he?
他是个很特别的人
He's someone very special.
一个让人难以忘怀的人
Someone impossible to forget,
不管我怎么努力
no matter how hard I might try.
希望我有天也能碰见这样一个人
I hope I meet someone like that someday.
我相信你会的
I'm sure you will.
当你遇见他们的时候
And when you meet them,
你就再无所求
you won't wish for anything else in the whole world.
米莉  马上上床去
Millie. Get to bed this instant.
好的
Yes.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们不需要你说对不起  爱丽丝
We don't need you to be sorry, Alice.
我们需要你变得好
We need you to be better.
如果你不愿意放弃这些傻事
And if you won't stop believing this foolishness,
至少不要对别人提及
at least have the decency to keep it to yourself.
我希望变好
I want to be.
我想要快乐
I want to be happy.
我在努力
I am trying.
努力的不够
Not nearly hard enough.
我们真以为你能忘记这些荒唐事  爱丽丝
We really thought you could forget this nonsense, Alice.
看来我们错了
It appears we were wrong.
好了  够了
All right, that's enough.
你不记得塞勒斯  也不记得自己
You don't remember Cyrus. You don't remember yourself.
但别再争了  我们走
Well, no more arguments. We're going.
去哪
Go where?
离开这鬼地方  看啊  爱丽丝
The hell out of here. Look, Alice!
看到这些树了吗  它们以前都是人
You see all these trees? They all used to be people.
如果留下来  你也会变这样
That's what's gonna happen to you if you stay.
所以我得把你带出去
So I'm getting you're out.
不要
No!
我不想走
I don't want to go!
我不走  离我远点
I'm not leaving! Stay away from me!
冷静  冷静点
Easy. Easy!
我不会走的  别想逼我离开
I won't go! You can't make me go!
别管我  让我留下来
Just leave me alone! Let me stay!
我不想伤害你  爱丽丝
I don't wanna hurt you, Alice,
但你已经不像你自己了
but you're not yourself.
我变得更好了  这才是我想要成为的人
I'm better! I'm the person I've always wanted to be!
我现在很开心
I'm happy!
这个地方让你以为自己很快乐
This place is making you happy!
这不是真的快乐
It's not real happiness!
相信我  我知道区别在哪
Believe me. I know the difference when I see it.
有什么区别
And why is that?!
听着  有些事我从没告诉过你
Listen. There's something I never told you before.
当我的心脏被夺走时
When my heart was ripped from me--
我是说  真的从我胸膛里被夺走时
I mean, literally taken from my chest--
我以为这个空洞永远都不会再被填满了
I thought that hole could never be filled.
但是你帮我拿了回来
And then you got it back for me.
从那时起  我没有好好地用心
Since then, I didn't really use it properly.
我一直觉得很愧疚
I always felt guilty about that.
好像我受之有愧
Like you gave me something more than I deserved.
好像我欠了你什么
Like I still owe you something.
也许正因如此我不能让你去送死
Maybe that's why I can't let this happen.
住手
Stop!
把剑给我  爱丽丝
Give me the sword, Alice!
爱丽丝  我不能逼你离开
Alice, I can't make you go.
没错
Exactly.
不  我说真的  我不能逼你
No, I mean it. I can't make you.
我不能带你走  不能强迫你离开
I can't take you. I can't force you.
因为在这个地方
Because this place--
唯一脱身的方法就是自愿离开
the only way out is wanting to go.
所以求你了  爱丽丝  跟我走吧
So please, Alice, just come with me.
该死的  爱丽丝  看看你自己
Oh, bloody hell, Alice. Look at ya!
跟我走吧
Please just come with me.
不要
No.
我哪都不会去
I'm not going anywhere.
我终于找到家了
I finally found a home.
如果我是个受到惊吓的小精灵
Now if I were a frightened little genie...
我会逃去哪呢
which way I would run?
真聪明
Clever.
但还不够
But not clever enough.
她在这里
Ah. There she is.
看来她没等我们吃早餐
Looks like she started breakfast without us.
爱丽丝  这就是我跟你说过的那个男孩
Alice. This is the boy I was telling you about--
达西夫人的儿子
Mrs. Darcy's son.
他只是顺便路过
He just stopped by.
我们觉得如果你感觉好些了
We thought he could join us for breakfast...
可以邀他一起吃早餐
if you were feeling better.
早上好  爱丽丝  很高兴见到你
Good morning, Alice. Nice to meet you.
是你把他带过来的
You brought him here?
你在想什么
And you thought what?
你以为这能让情况好转吗
That it would make things better?
帮我忘却往事吗
Help me forget?
你真的一点都不了解我
You really don't know me at all.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
反正不留在这儿
Anywhere else.
但是你无处可去了
But you have nowhere else to go.
你自己不也说过吗
Isn't that what you said?
快进去道歉
Go back in and apologize.
不可能
I won't.
你娶了一个自己不爱的人
Just because you married someone you don't love
不代表我也要这样做
doesn't mean I have to.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
她不能让你真的感到幸福
She doesn't make you truly happy.
她当然能了
Of course she does.
不能像妈妈那样
Not like mother.
我们不能在哀悼中
We can't... spend our whole life
度过余生  爱丽丝
in mourning, Alice.
你必须得走出阴影
You must find a way to move forward...
像我一样
as I did.
你用了好多年才忘掉妈妈
It took you years to get over mother.
在我小时候  你一直愁眉不展
You were sad my entire childhood.
你为什么觉得我在几天内
Why do you think I can forget Cyrus
就能忘记塞勒斯
in just a few days?
因为不像他  你妈妈是真实存在的
Because unlike him, your mother was bloody real!
塞勒斯也是
Cyrus was real.
不  他不是
No, he's not!
你得想办法忘记
You need to find a way to give up
你想象中的爱情故事  爱丽丝
this imaginary love story, Alice,
然后开始你自己的生活
and move on with your life.
要是我做不到呢
What if it's not possible?
如果一个人不管多努力
What if a person can't forget their love,
都无法忘记她的真爱呢
no matter how much easier it would be?
你必须忘记
You must.
我做不到
I can't.
那你就不能和我们一起
Then you can no longer live under our roof
住在这房子里
with our family.
这是你说的  还是她
Is that you talking, or her?
还有另一个好办法
There's one other.. good option.
伦敦有个医生  叫利德盖特
A doctor in London-- Lydgate.
他开了一家精神疗养院
He runs a psychiatric hospital.
疯人院
A madhouse?
那和书上写的不一样
It's not like it is in the books.
那个地方很好  很现代化
This place is very nice, very modern.
但是我没疯  你为什么不能相信我
But I'm not mad! Why can't you just believe--
你想让我相信什么
And what part do you want me to believe?
精灵还是会说话的兔子
The genie or the talking rabbit?
相信我
Me.
你应该相信我
You should believe in me!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们不能再这样下去了
We can't go on like this.
我必须为米莉着想
I have to think of Millie.
你会把我送进疯人院
You'll just send me to a madhouse.
不是把你送去
Not send you.
只是给你一个选择
Offer you a choice.
你可以让莎拉帮你找个丈夫
You can let Sarah find you a husband,
或者是去医院
or you can live in a hospital.
但是你不能留在这
But you can't sit here
渴望活在一个虚构的世界里  爱丽丝
pining for a make-believe life, Alice.
爱丽丝  决定权完全在你手上
The choice, Alice... is entirely yours.
没时间了  爱丽丝
Running out of time, Alice.
你必须做出选择
You have to make a choice.
别过来
Don't come any closer.
只有你想留下  这个地方才能留住你
This place can only make you stay if you want to.
所以我要帮你想起来
So I'm gonna help you remember,
就算要以生命为代价
even if it kills me.
记得这是谁给你的吗
You know who gave you this?
是塞勒斯
His name was Cyrus.
而你为了找到他  一直在艰苦地战斗
And you've been fighting like hell to get to him.
别说了  我在这里很开心
Stop it. I'm happy here.
你可以杀了我
You can kill me.
变成一棵该死的树
Become a bloody tree.
永远待在这里
Stay here forever.
但是没有塞勒斯  你是不会真的快乐
But you'll never be truly happy until you're with him.
我认识的爱丽丝绝不会在这一点上让步
The Alice I know would never give up on that.
拜托  别说了
Please stop it.
不
No.
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
这是什么东西
What are these?
放开我  让我走
Get off me! Let me go!
就是这样  棒极了  爱丽丝
Yes, that's it. Bloody brilliant, Alice!
我要去找他
I need to find him.
小心点  注意脚下
Careful now. Watch your step.
是你
You.
没错  就是我
Yes. Me.
是不是似曾相识
Look familiar?
一切都会好起来的  埃德温
It's going to be all right, Edwin.
你确定吗
Are you certain?
我们都很清楚留她不能留在这里
We both know she couldn't stay here.
她在那里会更开心的
She's going to be much happier.
所以你觉得她是做出了正确的选择
So you think she made the right decision?
我知道她做对了
I know she did.
我为她的聪明感到惊讶
I was actually surprised at her wisdom.
都会好起来的
It's going to be fine.
她不能永远做一个小女孩  埃德温
She can't be a little girl forever, Edwin,
而且医生会好好照顾她的
And he'll take excellent care of her.
我也希望如此
I certainly hope so.
她甚至都不想我到医院去看她
She doesn't even want me to visit the hospital, you know.
她还太过年轻鲁莽
She's still young and impetuous,
所以这样对她来说才是最好的
which is why this is best.
是时候让她成长起来了
It's time for her to grow up.
妈妈
Mommy?
谢谢
Thank you.
只是想报答你的救命之恩
Just trying to get square for once.
这样我就少欠你一个人情
That's one less I owe ya.
我还从没体会过那种感觉
I've never felt anything like that.
所有的烦恼  就在一瞬间消失了
All my troubles just-- just lifted away.
现在它们一下子又回来了
Now it's all just coming back all at once.
我的心好痛
There's this pain in my heart.
你也有这种感觉吗
Do you feel it, too?
一点没有
Nothing like that.
但你会没事的
But you're gonna be fine.
我刚解除石化状态时感觉也很糟
I mean, I felt like hell when I got out of that statue,
但瞧瞧我现在  焕如新生
But look at me now. Good as new.
谢谢你
Thank you for that.
谢什么
For what?
把我变回来
For turning me back.
不是我做的
That wasn't me.
不是你吗  那是谁
Wasn't you? Then who was it?
安娜斯塔西娅拿到了魔尘
Anastasia had a bit of magic dust.
该死的
Bloody hell.
什么
What?
你想继续当一座石像吗
You want to remain a statue?
我不想和她扯上关系
I want nothing to do with her.
她也许还爱着你  威尔
Perhaps she's still in love with you, Will.
我已经不再爱她了
Well, not only don't I love her back--
我做不到
I can't.
很早以前我就确认了这一点
I made sure of that a long time ago.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
跟你的心有关  对不对
It's about your heart, isn't it?
你说过有些事你还没告诉我
You said there was something you didn't tell me.
威尔  你欠我一个解释
Will? You owe me an explanation.
听着
Look...
我知道你历经许多艰险
I know you went to a lot of trouble
才找回我的心
to get my heart back, but...
但把我的心放回去并不能改变什么
But that place back there can't possibly affect it.
因为你根本就没有把心放回去
Because you never put it back in.
你都在想些什么啊
What were you thinking?
安娜斯塔西娅让我的心碎了
Anastasia broke my heart.
我知道一旦把心放回胸膛
I knew the minute I put it back in me chest,
我就会重新体会到心碎的感觉
I'd feel all that again.
你不想去感受
You didn't want to feel?
我不想
Not that.
所以我想  为什么不把这苦难留到明天
So I thought, why not put off the misery until tomorrow?
然后是后天  然后是大后天
Then the next tomorrow. Then the next.
过了一阵之后  我就有点习惯了
And after a while, I... I kinda got used to it...
那种空荡荡的感觉
the emptiness.
如果你没有把心放回胸膛的话
So if you didn't put your heart back in,
你把它藏到哪儿了
where did you put it?
晚点再告诉你  先看看这东西
I'll tell you later, because look at that bloody thing.
想要逃回到爱丽丝身边
It was a wonderful fantasy you had--
真是异想天开
escaping back to Alice.
这绝不只是异想天开
It's much more than a fantasy.
我会再见到她的
I will see her again.
现在你被困在一座漂浮小岛上
You're trapped on a floating island
无路可逃
with nowhere to escape.
亲爱的  残酷的现实就是
Darling, the harsh reality is
有时候仅仅有爱情是不够的
sometimes love is not enough.
恐怕你错了
I'm afraid you're wrong.
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
事实上  我相信我可以帮到你
Actually, I believe I can help you.
抱歉  我们认识吗
I'm sorry. Do we know one another?
不认识  但我认识你的女儿
No. But I know your daughter,
而且我知道她逃出疯人院后
and I know where she went after she escaped
去了什么地方
from that asylum.
爱丽丝吗
Alice?
你见过爱丽丝
You've seen Alice?
是的
Yes.
我还可以带你去见她
And I can take you to her.
仙
境
奇
缘
第一季  第六集
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译  wdjmhs  阿噻  茶炒栗子
翻译   欧沈娜  如是我闻
校对  wdjmhs  慕秋雪
精校  爵士年代蓬蓬裙
时间轴  萌  雨之
后期  吉吉
总监  wdjmhs